Contact

08026, Barcelona. 622580074 (Mobile) sarony11@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/saulfernandez-martinez (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Remote Working
Cloud Computing
Agile Project Management

Languages

English

Spanish

Catalan

Saul Fernandez Martinez

Senior System Administration in DevOps transition Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain

Summary

Senior Systems Administrator with strong management and leading skills, growing for my transition to DevOps specialist. Last years have helped me to specialize in project and budget management, designing strategies and setting goals with a proactive and problem-solving attitude.

Working in a remote work environment and using new technologies and methodologies for remote team working, communication, and collaboration.

I consider myself as a decisive, proactive and adaptable person with good social and management skills. It is easy to see me smiling and joking with my colleagues to improve the mood and helping in whatever might be needed. Ability to work under pressure, problem-solving and quick learner.

Experience

Barcelona Graduate School of Economics Senior System Administrator June 2016 - Present

Barcelona Area, Spain

Main Duties:

- Participating in setting goals and monitor IT budget (Jira, OKR)
- Developing a technical strategy to ensure alignment with its business goals
- Research and consultancy of new technological solutions
- Project Management for developing, implementing, and migrating projects (Jira, Trello, Agile)
- Create and leave written/visual documentation for new technologies and procedures (Confluence)
- Admin server apps, perimeter firewalls, planning disaster recovery strategies and backup plans, etc

Methodologies and Technologies

- Methodologies: Remote working, OKR, Agile, Jira, Confluence, Trello.
- OS: Windows 2012 R2, Debian 9, CentOS 7.
- Infrastructure: VMWare, Clouding Technology, App Engine, Kubernetes, GitHub

Semtechnologies IT Consultant and Project Manager January 2013 - Present Spain

Main Duties

- Project management versus deadline and budget
- Virtual infrastructure migration to the cloud
- Planning and saving concurrent infrastructure costs
- Leading technological transformation from office working to remote working
- Research and implement the most suitable IT solutions for a particular case.
- Finding IT solutions to business problems.
- Acting as middle man between business needs and technological reality.
- IT critical support and technical backup

Ciber

Service Engineering - Orange Spain R&D April 2012 - May 2013 (1 year 2 months)

Giving support to Orange, developing validations activities for the integration of new services and equipment in a pre-production enviorment. Also investigating key cases and reporting bugs. Working both as a team member or alone and attending meetings to keep a weekly report on the status of each project. Working Protocols: CPEs, DSLAM, Voice Services, SIP, DHCP, PPP, IPTV, DLNA, M2M, GPON, Alcatel-Lucent IMS.

Iss iMedia

System and Security Administrator & Technical Support May 2011 - November 2011 (7 months)

Prat de Llobregat

Working as network and system administrator a network with 80 hosts and Windows Server 2008, Mac OS, CentOS, Cisco and Asterisk. Giving both helpdesk support and working with highest critical functions.

*The company ceased operations in Spain for 2012

Xifring

IT Consultant

May 2010 - May 2011 (1 year 1 month)

Barcelona

Working with many customers, offering dedicated consultantcy, implantation and managment of system and network administration services. Using Microsoft (Windows 2008 R2 and Core), Mac OS X Server and Fortigate for perimiter security and VPN connectivity and many other specific softwares.

Teamlog Iberica

1° and 2° level network technician

February 2010 - April 2010 (3 months)

Prat del Llobregat

Working for HP client giving worldwide support (Fortum, Ericsson or Santander Bank). 1° and 2° level network problem solving using Cisco and Juniper firewalls tecnologies.

*This was a temporary job.

Self-employed

IT Consultant & Technician

June 2008 - December 2009 (1 year 7 months)

Royal Leamington Spa

Offering IT services to many clients, particulars and companies. Backups, 24/7 emergency assistance, system administration, security auditory and technical consultancy.

Education

Warwickshire College

National Diploma in IT Support, IT · (2007 - 2009)

Warwickshire College

National Diploma in IT & Business, IT · (2007 - 2009)

IES Fuente San Luis

FP Superior Programación, IT Programming · (2006 - 2007)